# BEVAN JACINTO

 $+91~9930562544 \diamond Mumbai, MH$ 

### **OBJECTIVE**

I am a software developer primarily focusing on building fullstack solutions using Angular and React along with NodeJS, Express and MongoDB. I also work on building cross-platform applications using Flutter, Dart and firebase for the backend. Over the course of my academic and professional career I have gained valuable expertise on these tools and with over 2 years of experience in building frontend and backend services I am eager to take on the next challenge that awaits me.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science - Computer Science and Engineering, Santa Clara University, CA, USA Bachelor of Engineering - Information Technology, University of Mumbai

June 2023 October 2020

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, Typescript, Dart, C/C++, Windows, Linux

Database: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, Angular, React, Bootstrap, Chakra UI, Material UI, NodeJS, Express, PHP, Ajax

Software and tools: NLTK, Docker, Git/Github, Flutter, Figma, Vite, Redux, Arduino, XAMPP

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer

Sept 2023 - Aug 2024

SCU Frugal Innovation Hub

Santa Clara, CA

- Developed and implemented user interface (UI/UX) designs utilizing technologies such as **HTML**, **CSS**, **Bootstrap**, and **Angular**, ensuring a responsive and user-friendly experience.
- Designed and developed data visualization web dashboards using Angular, TypeScript, and HighchartsJS to present key metrics clearly and effectively.
- Created and integrated APIs using **NodeJS** and **Express** to retrieve and display data from a **MongoDB** database, ensuring seamless data flow and real-time updates in dashboards.
- Provided visual and tabular representations of critical KPIs (Key Performance Indicators) such as user engagement and retention rates, supporting data-driven decision-making.
- Achieved a significant reduction in manual data queries (by 80%), streamlining the process of generating reports and enhancing the accuracy and speed of performance analysis for key business metrics.

#### Software Engineer

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

Rocket Central

Detroit, MI

- Crafted validation scripts using **Joi** (data validator) for multiple forms in the mortgaging application flow using **Angular** and **Typescript** to ensure accurate prediction of mortgage rates.
- Used the Rocket Mortgage API to persist users mortgage application progress and data for smooth retrieval at a later point in the future.
- Leveraging Git and GitHub for code management, version control and continuous integration.
- Created different UI views using **HTML**, **CSS** and **Typescript** for different clients originating through one of the many Rocket Mortgage partners.

### Graduate Engineer Trainee

Sep 2020 - July 2021

Reliance Jio

Mumbai, India

- Collaborated closely with the market research and data analysis teams to conduct surveys and gather valuable insights on the product experiences of the newly launched video conferencing application, Jiomeet.
- Played a key role in ensuring high-quality user experiences and customer satisfaction for multiple Jio products.
- Worked collaboratively with cross-functional teams, including **market research** and **data analysis**, to gather and analyze user feedback and insights.
- Demonstrated leadership skills in overseeing **service validation** activities and ensuring the successful deployment of releases.

## Software Engineer Intern

Tata Consultancy Services

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019 Mumbai, India

- Created a Machine Learning based classifier in **Python** using Natural Language Processing (NLP) to categorize Tata Consultancy Services employee claim reports into seven distinct categories using **NLTK** (Natural Language Toolkit).
- Leveraged Anaconda Python for preprocessing of data using stemming and lemmatization.
- Used **Git** for collaborative version control and code review, ensuring efficient code management.
- Developed an organizational solution that effectively bridged communication between 10,000 employees and the Human Resources department, resulting in significant time savings of up to 70% previously spent on manual processes.

## **PROJECTS**

#### STOCK MARKET PREDICTION USING MACHINE LEARNING:

- Developed an LSTM model achieving an 85% prediction accuracy for stock prices using Python.
- Engineered a software application for deploying the machine learning model, leveraging Tkinter, Scikit-learn, Pandas, NumPy, and TensorFlow libraries.

#### **MEDLABS:**

- Created a dynamic website from the ground up, employing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for the front-end development.
- Engineered the back-end infrastructure of the website using PHP and MySQL, incorporating a robust shopping cart system.

#### **GAME HUB:**

- Developed a game listing website clone using React, Vite, and Typescript.
- Integrated frontend frameworks including Chakra UI and Bootstrap to enhance the user interface and experience.
- Implemented data fetching from the RAWG API to dynamically populate and display games in a grid format on the webpage.